

Shibu V. S

Team Lead & PHP, WordPress Developer

Contact

Address

Thiruvanathapuram, India 695605

Phone

+917907239353

E-mail

shibuvs89@gmail.com

Skills

PHP

Advanced

WordPress

Advanced

Laravel

Intermediate

GIT

Advanced

JAVASCRIPT

Advanced

REACT JS

Intermediate

Enthusiastic, positive and self-driven professional with 11+ years of IT experience in web development and adept in developing websites, web applications and ecommerce sites. Aspiring to establish a career in a challenging environment where knowledge and acquired skills can be exploited to achieve organizational goals and career advancement.

Work History

2022-10 -Current

Senior Technical Support Engineer(PHP, WordPress)

ANSYS, Bengaluru, India (Remote)

- Website Development: Led the development efforts for Ansys websites, including AnsysGPT, forum, community, storefront and the Ansys KM site. Collaborated with cross-functional teams to translate business requirements into scalable and user-friendly web solutions, ensuring optimal performance and reliability.
- As an Ansys Developer specializing in website and community platforms, I played a pivotal role in the design, development, and maintenance of various Ansys online properties.
- Gained strong leadership skills by managing projects from start to finish.
- Used different APIs to build frameworks.
- Mentored junior developers on industry best practices and techniques.

2021-06 -2022-10

PHP & WordPress Developer | Development Team Leader

NCDA SERVICES PRIVATE LIMITED, Ernakulam, India

- Follow the scope of an online project that goes from the proposal stage, to the technical work up, and finally to the delivery of the web product.
- Participate in the initial conception stage along with a client in order to better meet the needs of the customer and to translate those expectations to employees.
- Design solutions for customer problems related to ecommerce and other website presence issues.
- Lead the design process of a website by working with a team of graphic designers and web

developers.

Languages

English, Hindi, Malayalam, Tamil 2020-07 -2021-05

Full Stack Wordpress Web Developer

Appstation pvt.ltd

- Leveraged strong understanding of WordPress core to manipulate admin and theme components.
- Implemented and assessed performance of SEO best practices.
- Developed and implemented WordPress sites, themes and plugins.
- Referenced web analytics reporting to enhance designs and improve site performance.
- Collaborated with end users on project specifications, strategy and execution to build new WordPress pages and update existing ones.

2019-09 -2020-03

WordPress Developer & Laravel

Inviser Enterprises pvt.Itd

- Created and updated re-usable code libraries to streamline WordPress development cycle.
- Leveraged strong understanding of WordPress core to manipulate admin and theme components.
- Delivered quality commercial websites that met coding standards and cross-browser compatibilities.
- Installed required plugins and additional coding to fit final design and functionality requirements.
- Implemented and assessed performance of SEO best practices.

2016-12 -2019-08

PHP Developer & WordPress Developer

Cochin Techs & Solutions

- Wrote server-side and client-side code for Web projects using PHP, HTML, CSS and JavaScript.
- Developed back-end components to connect applications with web services.
- Built and maintained internal tools to streamline software development process and enhance productivity.

 Collaborated with project managers and developers to define parameters and plan detailed specifications with clear project deliverables and timelines.

2013-09 -2016-12

Web Developer

Integralsoft Tech

- Integralsoft Tech is a leading web and app development in Kochi, India, supporting clients from USA and Australia
- Worked on projects for Raspberries (Warmze) and Hyden (Hakuba Powder Tours)
- The e-commerce websites were developed using WordPress design integration, WooCommerce, PHP and plugin development of CMS
- Accountable for development and modification of customized Content Management Systems

2012-03 -2013-03

PHP Developer

Random Logics Technology

- The company specializes in offering customer oriented professional and custom web design services
- Worked on design and development of club websites using PHP/MySQL for Japanese and Australian clients
- Developed club based website catering to luxury environment for customers with the highest standard of customer service using PHP and MySQL
- Worked on developing and updating web applications using Ajax, PHP and MySQL by coordinating with the technical director on current projects

2011-05 -2011-11

WinWrench ASP.Net Trainee

Winwrench

- WinWrench is an in-house digital solutions company based in Trivandrum, India
- Worked on development of Hostel Management System using ASP.Net and MySQL

- Enhanced skillset of designing principles and software development approach
- Developed system for student or staff registration with payment and leave details

Education

2007-04 **12th (HSE)**

Board of Higher Secondary Education - Kerala

2011-04 Bachelor of Engineering: Computer

Science and Engineering

Anna university - Tirunelveli, Tamil Nadu

Certifications

2021-10 Complete WordPress Developer Course - Plugins &

Themes